

## **Andrea Hill**

## **UX Research and Product Strategy**



## **Summary**

User Experience Researcher with over 15 years of experience researching, designing and developing innovative, web-based products. Possesses the trifecta of empathic listening, technical skills and business acumen. Applies these skills to inform product decisions, on both early-concept- and existing products and services.



### **Experience**

2018 present

### Sr UX Specialist (UX Research and Design)

### **LexisNexis**

- Oversees the integration of, or variation from, global UX standards to meet the needs of the Canadian market
- · Conducts qualitative research to inform design and strategy
- · Prepares wireframes and prototypes for concept testing
- Supports product and engineering teams in end-to-end UX strategy and design
- Works with the data and engineering teams to ensure features are appropriately tagged and indexed for data analysis

2017 -2018-05

# Innovation Consultant (UX Research and Product Strategy) Frameplay

- Established a consultancy to assist mid-sized organizations with customer research and product strategy
- Analyzed quantitative and qualitative research to prioritize the roadmap for a client's customer support portal.
- Conducted customer interviews to uncover unmet customer needs to drive product strategy for a B2B customer engagement platform

2016 -2017

# Manager of Innovation Strategy (UX Research and Product Strategy)

### ReadyTalk

- Prepared the business case for a dedicated Innovation team
- Managed and mentored a team of Business/Customer Insight Analysts to identify new product and service offerings
- Facilitated Design Sprints with cross-functional teams to identify new products and features
- Introduced "Jobs-to-be-Done" as a framework for understanding customer needs
- Designed and managed the MVP development for "FoxDen Connect" -ReadyTalk's in-room conferencing solution

# Product Strategist / Intrapreneur (UX Research and Product Strategy)

### ReadyTalk

As Intrapreneur:

• Launched the company's first internal startup (UbiMeet) to capitalize on an



### Address

Ottawa Canada

### E-mail

andrea.hill@gmail.com

#### **Portfolio**

afhill.com/portfolio

### LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/afhill

### **Twitter**

twitter.com/afhill



Diagramming and Journey Mapping



Design Thinking



Information Architecture



Interaction Design



Jobs to be Done



Product Strategy



Prototyping



Survey Design



**Usability Testing** 



User Interviews



Workshop Facilitation





2013 -

2016

- opportunity identified through customer research
- Conducted ongoing customer development to drive towards productmarket fit
- · Managed the product roadmap, backlog and customer support
- · Directly managed the team's engineers

As Product Strategist:

- Produced MSDs (Marketing Strategy Documents), communicating product features/capabilities
- Worked with cross-functional team members (product owners, engineering, marketing) to ensure products meet user needs
- · Monitored competitors, industry shifts and emerging markets
- Established the "Customer Insights Team": a panel of customers willing to be contacted for research purposes
- Planned and managed beta testing for new feature and service releases

Sr. Idea Designer (UX Research and Design)

**LexisNexis (Customer Discovery and Innovation)** 

- Owned new product and feature concept development, from problem discovery through high level UI design and concept validation
- Translated customer data/analytics into actionable insights and feature enhancement recommendations
- Developed IA/UX artifacts including customer personas, wireframes and user stories
- · Worked with product planners and tech leads to inform the roadmap

Director of Product (Product Management and Development Manager)

**Worldways Social Marketing** 

- Consulted with clients to assess their organizational readiness and capabilities in implementing a digital marketing strategy
- · Prepared and delivered high-quality strategic proposals to clients
- · Designed and developed the agency's first syndicated digital product
- Managed technical product development

Sr. Developer / Business Analyst

**Resource Interactive (acquired by IBM)** 

- Documented UI requirements for clients including The Limited and The Scotts Miracle-Gro Company.
- Provided web accessibility strategy and support for clients including
   Hewlett Packard, Bose Corporation, The Limited and Procter & Gamble.
- Business user and developer trained for ATG e-Commerce Suite for Personalization

Sr. Web Developer / Accessibility Coordinator

**LexisNexis (User Experience)** 

- Established a library of UI Building Blocks to be leveraged across product suites to streamline development time, enhance usability and increase overall product quality
- Developed high-fidelity prototypes for usability testing. Worked with external facilitators to refine scenarios. Attended testing in Chicago (2005), New York City (2004, 2006) and Los Angeles (2004).
- · Oversaw the creation of a cross-disciplinary accessibility team
- Served as the user experience representative on the Architecture Advisory Board and Web2.0 working group



Application of Artificial Intelligence

**Business Plan Preparation** 

**Decision Modeling and Applications** 

Entrepreneurship

Game Design Master Class

**Human Computer Interaction** 

IT & Business Strategy

Information Design

Jobs to be Done (ODI) Master Class

Market Intelligence

**Marketing Management** 

Marketing Strategy

New Product Development

Psycholinguistics

Strategy

System Architecture and Engineering

2008 -

2012

2007 -

2008

2003 -

2007

2012 -

2013

2

## **Education**

2014

University of Colorado at Boulder: MBA (Strategy & Entrepreneurship)

2008

Franklin University: MS (Computer Science)

2003

Franklin University: BS (Digital Communications)

2002

**Sessions School of Design: Certificate (Graphic Design)**